KHALED HASSAN HARMOUCHE

Lebanese Citizen Beirut-Lebanon Married DOB 05/02/1962

+961-3-893355 Kawsanh@hotmail.com

Dedicated Managing Director-Owner with more than 20 years of experience providing clients with the highest degree of Hospitality and Customer Service by ensuring that facilities meet and exceed expectations. Strong leader possessing outstanding work ethic and integrity, always dedicated to meeting budget and meticulously documenting financials. Manage by leading and showing staff the rewards and encouraging them to exceed their own expectations to provide the best Service and Customer satisfaction.

Professional experience

2003-Present **Managing Director**

Beirut Lebanon BeauRivage Hotel

Overseeing the daily functions and setting expectations for Engineering, Housekeeping, Food & Beverage, Front Desk Department and Managing more than 80 Employees.

- Oversaw Hotel Renovation
- Hired and Trained new team for the Hotel
- Created and Maintained Budget
- Ensure Quality Services
- Researched and Selected new Products and Inventory

Executive Assistant Manager

1998-2003

Beirut – Lebanon BeauRivage Hotel

In charge of Sales and Marketing and reporting directly to the General Manager

Managing Partner-Owner

The SHOGUN Lounge – Japanese and Chinese Fine Dining Cuisine 2004-2018

Verdun & Downtown Beirut-Franchise in KSA and Kuwait

Director of Sales and Marketing 1995-1998

Beirut - Lebanon BeauRivage Hotel

Front Office Manager 1992-1995

Beirut – Lebanon BeauRivage Hotel

Assistant Front Office Manager 1991-1992

Beirut – Lebanon BeauRivage Hotel

Guest Service Representative - On The Board Of Energy & Safety Committee 1989-1991

Holiday Inn Convention Center –Budget Inn Hammond-Louisiana, USA

Assistant Production Manager and Public Relations (Part Time) 1978-1980

Cosmoplast Industrial Company Sharjah, UAE

Life guard (Summers) 1977-1979

Carlton Hotels Company Sharjah, UAE

Education

Bachelor of Science, Industrial Management Technology (1986)

Southeastern Louisiana University-Manufacturing Technologist

Hammond, La 70402-USA

International Baccalaureate of Switzerland- Part I (1980)

National College of Choueifat

National College of Choueifat, Dubai-UAE (1975)

Skills

- Excellent Manager who leads by example and through installing confidence in staff, leading to higher productivity and better client satisfaction.
- Skilled in the principles of Administration and Management in the Service Industry, including Strategic Planning, Production Methods, Human Resources, and the Coordination of People and Resources.
- Excels in Sales and Marketing, including Showing, Promoting, and Selling.
- Critical Thinker who uses logic and reason to identify and evaluate situations and their alternative solutions.
- Strong Communication Skills that allows me to easily determine Guest and Employee concerns.
- Excellent in Public Relations with Various Good Contacts.

Accomplishments

- Mayor of SemQanieh City Shouf-Lebanon 2004-2016 (Two Terms)
- Winner of Two Grumpy Gourmet Awards Amman-Jordan, Best Sushi Restaurant-SHOGUN
- MUBS University, Mayor Appreciation Award 2015
- President of Lebanese Billiard Federation 2012-2013
- Arab Billiard Federation, Board of Directors, Representative of Lebanon 1999-2013
- Vice President, Lebanese Billiard Federation 1998-2011
- Auxiliary Deputy Marshal, Hammond-Louisiana USA, Feb. 1986-2014.
- Certificate from Monaco International Consultants Lebanon
- Certificate from Hotel Management System Training Program, Holiday Inn Convention Center- USA
- Outstanding Performance for Excellent Customer Service, Holiday Inn Convention Center- USA
- Member of Lebanese Boy Scouts
- Recipient of the Key to the City of Hammond, Louisiana, USA Feb. 1983
- Secretary Treasurer, Tangipahoa Practical Shooters Association 1989-1990 -USA
- Recipient of Honorary Citizenship Award, City of Hammond May 1981 & June 1994- USA

Languages

Arabic-English (Fluently Read-Spoken-Written)

Activities

Captain of Soccer Team-Southeastern Louisiana University Hammond-Louisiana USA 1983-1986 Head Soccer Coach-South Tangi Youth Soccer Association Hammond-Louisiana USA 1981-1983

Hobbies

Scuba Diving, Horseback Riding, Hunting, Fishing, Soccer, Volleyball